livezilla.com 2019-07-24

# Disclaimer & Privacy Policy for LiveZilla Live Chat Software

## Data Privacy Policy Statement

Our website may be used without entering personal information. Different rules may apply to certain services on our site, however, and are explained separately below. We collect personal information from you (e.g. name, address, email address, telephone number, etc.) in accordance with the provisions of German data protection statutes. Information is considered personal if it can be associated exclusively to a specific natural person. The legal framework for data protection may be found in the GDPR and the Telemedia Act (TMG). The provisions below serve to provide information as to the manner, extent and purpose for collecting, using and processing personal information by the provider. 

LiveZilla GmbH, Ekkehardstraße 10, 78224 Singen  
Telephone: +49 7731 / 9266401  
support@livezilla.net 

An in-house data protection officer is not appointed, as there is no legal requirement for such an appointment. 

Please be aware that data transfer via the internet is subject to security risks and, therefore, complete protection against third-party access to transferred data cannot be ensured. 

## Copyright

The author intends not to use any copyrighted material for the publication or, if not possible, to indicate the copyright of the respective object. The copyright for any material created by the author is reserved. Any duplication or use of objects such as images, diagrams, sounds or texts in other electronic or printed publications is not permitted without the author's agreement. LiveZilla is a registered Trademark of LiveZilla GmbH. 

## Cookies

Our website makes use of so-called cookies in order to recognize repeat use of our website by the same user/internet connection subscriber. Cookies are small text files that your internet browser downloads and stores on your computer. They are used to improve our website and services. In most cases these are so-called "session cookies" that are deleted once you leave our website. To an extent, however, these cookies also pass along information used to automatically recognize you. Recognition occurs through an IP address saved to the cookies. The information thereby obtained is used to improve our services and to expedite your access to the website. You can prevent cookies from being installed by adjusting the settings on your browser software accordingly. You should be aware, however, that by doing so you may not be able to make full use of all the functions of our website. 

Name | Provider | Purpose | Lifetime | Type | Category  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
lz_geo_city | LiveZilla GmbH | Geolocation (City), used to determine the geographical location of website visitors. | 1 Year | HTTP Cookie | Statistic  
lz_geo_ctryiso | LiveZilla GmbH | Geolocation (Country), used to determine the geographical location of website visitors. | 1 Year | HTTP Cookie | Statistic  
lz_geo_data | LiveZilla GmbH | Geolocation (Timestamp), used to determine the geographical location of website visitors. | 1 Year | HTTP Cookie | Statistic  
lz_geo_isp | LiveZilla GmbH | Geolocation (ISP), used to determine the geographical location of website visitors. | 1 Year | HTTP Cookie | Statistic  
lz_geo_lat | LiveZilla GmbH | Geolocation (Latitude), used to determine the geographical location of website visitors. | 1 Year | HTTP Cookie | Statistic  
lz_geo_long | LiveZilla GmbH | Geolocation (Longitude), used to determine the geographical location of website visitors. | 1 Year | HTTP Cookie | Statistic  
lz_geo_region | LiveZilla GmbH | Geolocation (Region), used to determine the geographical location of website visitors. | 1 Year | HTTP Cookie | Statistic  
lz_geo_tz | LiveZilla GmbH | Geolocation (Timezone), used to determine the geographical location of website visitors. | 1 Year | HTTP Cookie | Statistic  
lz_last_visit | LiveZilla GmbH | Last Visit (Timestamp), used to determine when the website visitor browsed the website the last time. | 1 Year | HTTP Cookie | Statistic  
lz_userid | LiveZilla GmbH | Sets up a unique ID which is used to generate statistical data about the website visitor's usage of the website. | 1 Year | HTTP Cookie | Statistic  
lz_visits | LiveZilla GmbH | Number of visits, is used to identify how often the website visitor already visited the website. | 1 Year | HTTP Cookie | Statistic  
cookie_accepted | LiveZilla GmbH | Used to determine if website visitor has confirmed data privacy / cookie notification. | 1 Year | HTTP Cookie | Required  
  
## Server Data

For technical reasons, data such as the following, which your internet browser transmits to us or to our web space provider (so called server log files), is collected: - type and version of the browser you use - operating system - websites that linked you to our site (referrer URL) - websites that you visit - date and time of your visit - your Internet Protocol (IP) address. This anonymous data is stored separately from any personal information you may have provided, thereby making it impossible to connect it to any particular person. The data is used for statistical purposes in order to improve our website and services. 

## Purpose of Registering

We offer you the opportunity to sign up for our website. The information entered when signing up, as shown in the registration (Name, address, email address and as the case maybe tradde ID) form is collected and stored solely for use by our website. When signing up for our website, we also store your IP address and the date and time you registered. This serves to protect us in the event a third party improperly and without your knowledge makes use of your data to sign up for our site. None of this information is transferred to third parties. Nor is any of this information matched to any information that may be collected by other components of our website. 

## Newsletter

Our website offers you the opportunity to subscribe to our newsletter. The newsletter provides you periodically with information about our services. To receive our newsletter, we require a valid email address. We will review the email address you provide for the purpose of determining whether you are in fact the owner of the email address provided or whether the actual owner of said address is authorized to receive the newsletter. When subscribing to our newsletter, we will store your IP address as well as the date and time you subscribed. This serves to protect us in the event a third party improperly and without your knowledge makes use of your email address to subscribe to our newsletter. We will not collect any other data. The data thereby collected is used solely for the purpose of receiving our newsletter. No data is transferred to third parties. Nor is any of this information matched to any information that other components of our website may collect. You may cancel your subscription to the newsletter at any time. You will find additional details in the email confirming your subscription as well as in each newsletter. 

## Contacting Us

On our website we offer you the opportunity to contact us, either by email and/or by using a contact form. In such event, information provided by the user is stored for the purpose of facilitating communications with the user. No data is transferred to third parties. Nor is any of this information matched to any information that may be collected by other components of our website. 

## Referrals and links

The author is not responsible for any contents linked or referred to from his pages - unless he has full knowledge of illegal contents and would be able to prevent the visitors of his site fromviewing those pages. If any damage occurs by the use of information presented there, only the author of the respective pages might be liable, not the one who has linked to these pages. Furthermore the author is not liable for any postings or messages published by users of discussion boards, guestbooks or mailinglists provided on his page. 

## Use of YouTube components with enhanced data protection mode

On our website we use components (videos) of YouTube, LLC 901 Cherry Ave., 94066 San Bruno, CA, USA, a company belonging to Google Inc., Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. To this end, we use the - enhanced data protection mode - option provided by YouTube. When you display a page that has an embedded video, a connection will be made to the YouTube server and the content will appear on the website via a communication to your browser. According to the information provided by YouTube, in - enhanced data protection mode -, data is only transferred to the YouTube server, in particular which of our websites you have visited, if you watch the video. If you are logged onto YouTube at the same time, this information will be matched to your YouTube member account. You can prevent this from happening by logging out of your member account before visiting our website. 

Further information about data protection by YouTube is provided by Google under the following link: 

https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy/ 

## Use of Google Analytics with anonymization function

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA, hereafter "Google". Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies", text files that are stored on your computer and thereby allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by these cookies, such as the time, location and frequency of your website visit, including your IP address, is transmitted to Google in the United States and stored there. We use Google Analytics on our website with an IP anonymization feature. In this case, your IP address will already be shortened and thus anonymised by Google within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of our site, to compile reports on our website activity, and to provide other services related to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties if required by law or as far as third parties process this data on behalf of Google. Google does not claim to link your IP address to any other data provided by Google. You can prevent the installation of cookies by setting your browser software accordingly; however, we point out that in this case you may not be able to fully use all functions of our website. In addition, Google offers a deactivation option for the most popular browsers, giving you more control over what data Google collects and processes. If you enable this option, website visit information will not be sent to Google Analytics. Activation does not prevent information from being transmitted to us or any other web analytics services we may use. For more information about Google's opt-out option and to enable this option, please visit the following link: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en 

## Use of Google Adwords

We also use the Google advertising tool "Google Adwords" to promote our website. As part of this, we use the "Conversion Tracking" analytics service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA, "Google", on our website. If you have reached our website via a Google ad, a cookie will be stored on your computer. Cookies are small text files that your Internet browser stores and saves on your computer. These so-called "conversion cookies" lose their validity after 30 days and are not used for your personal identification. If you visit certain pages on our website and the cookie has not expired yet, we and Google may recognize that you, as a user, clicked on one of our Google ads and were redirected to our site. The information obtained through the "Conversion Cookies" is used by Google to create visitor statistics for our website. These statistics tell us the total number of users who clicked on our ad, and which pages on our site were subsequently accessed by their respective users. However, we or other advertisers do not receive any information through "Google Adwords" that personally identifies users. You can prevent the installation of the "conversion cookies" by setting your browser accordingly, for example by setting a browser that generally deactivates the automatic setting of cookies or specifically blocks only cookies from the domain "googleadservices.com". Google's privacy policy can be found at the following link: https://services.google.com/sitestats/en.html 

## Use of Google Remarketing

We use the Google Remarketing service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA, hereinafter "Google", on our website. Google Remarketing can show ads to people who have already visited our website in the past. Within the Google ad network, advertisements tailored to their interests can be displayed on our site. Google Remarketing uses cookies for this evaluation. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer and allow an analysis of the use of the website. This will allow us to recognize our visitors as soon as they visit websites within Google's advertising network. In this way, within the Google ad network, advertisements may be presented that relate to content that the visitor previously viewed on Google Network websites that also use Google's remarketing feature. Google does not collect any personal data. You can disable this feature if you make the appropriate settings at http://www.google.com/settings/ads. 

## Use of Facebook Remarketing

This website uses the remarketing feature "Custom Audiences" of Facebook Inc. ("Facebook"). This function serves to present to visitors of this website, as part of their visit to the social network Facebook, interest-based advertisements ("Facebook Ads"). For this purpose, the Facebook remarketing tag was implemented on this website. Through this tag, a direct connection to the Facebook servers is made when visiting the website. It is transmitted to the Facebook server that you have visited this website and Facebook assigns this information to your personal Facebook user account. For more information on the collection and use of data by Facebook, as well as your rights in this regard and ways to protect your privacy, please refer to the privacy policy of Facebook at https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/. Alternatively, you can disable the remarketing feature "Custom Audiences" at https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_=_. For this you must be logged in to Facebook. 

## Use of LiveZilla

On our site, we use components of LiveZilla GmbH, Ekkehardstrasse 10, 78224 Singen. These components collect and store data from every single visit to the site for the purposes of web analysis and the operation of a live chat system. This data can then be used to generate pseudonymised user profiles via the deployment of cookies. These user profiles can assist with the analysis of visitor behaviour and of the operation of the live chat system and may be evaluated in order to improve our Internet provision and to enable us to design our site in a way that meets user needs. 

## Information/Cancellation/Deletion

On the basis of the Federal Data Protection Act, you may contact us at no cost if you have questions relating to the collection, processing or use of your personal information, if you wish to request the correction, blocking or deletion of the same, or if you wish to cancel explicitly granted consent. Please note that you have the right to have incorrect data corrected or to have personal data deleted, where such claim is not barred by any legal obligation to retain this data.
